A Guide to The Papers of Fredson Thayer Bowers, [1595-1902], 1922-1992
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
The Papers of Fredson Thayer Bowers [1595-1902], 1922-1992
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12730-a
The Papers of Fredson Thayer Bowers contain ca. 12,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Except for a portion of correspondence whose access is under the control of donor Matthew J. Bruccoli, the balance of the Fredson Thayer Bowers Papers is without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection is a consolidation of gift acquisitions received in the Manuscript and Special Collections Departments of the University of Virginia over the period 1950-94 from: Fredson Bowers, the Estate of Fredson T. Bowers, Matthew J. Bruccoli, John Denniston, George W. Williams and Jo-Ann Boydston.
Biographical/Historical Information
Fredson Thayer Bowers was born in New Haven, Connecticut on April 25, 1905. Although he was the only child of Fredson Eugene Bowers and Hattie May Quigley, he grew up with two half-sisters (the children of his mother's previous marriage) and a stepfather, Charles K. Groesbeck, who his mother married after his father's death in 1911.
Bowers entered Brown University at age 16 after graduating from New Haven General High School in 1921. His study interests were in English literature and music, both of which he pursued with vigor. He was a member of Phi Beta Kappa and participated in a variety of literary, music and student activity clubs. He edited the school newspaper and served on the boards of student publications. He played the Hawaiian guitar, the saxophone and led a jazz band. On November 11, 1924, at age 19, while still an undergraduate, he married Hyacinth Adeline Sutphin, a Smith College graduate and member of a New York Social Register family.
Bowers graduated from Brown in 1925 and spent the next nine years at Harvard doing graduate study and raising a family. A son, Fredson, was born in 1927, a daughter, Joan, in 1931, and twin sons, Peter and Stephen, in 1934. Bowers taught English, tutored in modern languages and developed a passion for breeding, showing, judging and writing about Irish wolfhounds. He earned his Ph.D in February, 1934 and the next year went to England on scholarship.
In 1936, following an episode of marital problems that had led to a divorce, Bowers took an instructorship at Princeton. He taught freshman English and did editing work on Thomas Dekker until he accepted an offer from Dean James Southall Wilson to serve as acting assistant professor at the University of Virginia, which remained his home for the rest of his life. At the University of Virginia, Bowers taught English along with 17th and 18th century novels and a course in introductory bibliography. In 1942, he married Nancy Hale, and relocated with her to wartime Washington, D.C. where he served as a Naval Commander supervising the deciphering of enemy codes.
Bowers' impressive scholarship during his early years in Charlottesville resulted in his recognition as a preeminent authority of bibliographical analysis. His ideas and methods broke new ground and challenged established principles and methods in descriptive bibliography and textual criticism. In this period, he inaugurated the publication of Studies in Bibliography which he personally edited for more than 40 years and developed into a journal of worldwide repute. In 1949, he published Principles of Bibliographical Description, which became and remains a major resource in the history of bibliography. His prestigious lectures and the voluminous output of his published essays and research together with his activities on and leadership of professional associations marked him as a dynamic scholar in his field. As a teacher of boundless energy and as an active and innovative chairman and dean, Bowers built the English department at the University of Virginia into one of the best in the United States. Bowers still found time to teach summer courses at the University of Chicago and to pursue his hobbies: writing music reviews each week for the Richmond Times- Dispatch and publishing articles about his beloved wolfhounds and his philatelic interests.
During his later career years, Bowers turned his scholarship skills in textual criticism to editing the works of post-medieval writers. He published dozens of edited volumes (60 between 1960 and his death) creating distinct expressions of technique and methodology that became recognized among many as the "Bowers school of editing." He continued producing large numbers of essays, lectures and reviews beyond his retirement in 1975.
Throughout his notable career, Bowers was the recipient of numerous awards and recognitions. Among the many were honorary degrees from Clark and Brown Universities and the University of Chicago. He received the Gold Medal of the Bibliographical Society in London and his own University of Virginia recognized his many achievements with its highest honor, the Thomas Jefferson Award as well as two endowed chairs, the Alumni Professorship of English (1957-68) and the Linden Kent Memorial Professorship (1968-75, 1975-91 (Emeritus)). Bowers also held appointments to the Fulbright, Guggenheim, Rosenbach, Woodrow Wilson National and the Academy of Arts and Sciences fellowships. In 1974, Bowers was honored by his former Virginia and Chicago students at a retirement dinner and in 1985, on the occasion of his eightieth birthday, his colleagues organized an international conference on bibliography and editing in his name at the University of Virginia.
Nancy Hale, whose health had been failing for several years, died in 1988 and Bowers, who had also begun suffering with major health problems, died a few years later on April 11, 1991, at age 86. Following cremation, his ashes were buried next to the grave of Nancy Hale at Forest Hills Cemetery in Jamaica Plain, Boston.
Scope and Content Information
The Papers of Fredson Thayer Bowers contain ca. 12,000 items (45 shelf feet) that span the years 1595-1992, with the bulk concentrated in the period 1922-1992. The items relating to pre-twentieth century dates consist primarily of photo and electrostatic copies (EC's) of printed literary texts that Bowers used in his editing work. Among these, the largest portion are copies of Stephen Crane stories that appearedin newspapers in the late 19th and early 20th centuries.
Arrangement
Processing Information
The original classification numbers (listed below) of all previous acquisitions in this collection have been redesignated under a single consolidated classification number: 12730-a
Manuscript numbers: 3491; 5164; 5219; 5219-a; 5691,-a-ac,-ae,-ag-ai,-ak-al; 10204-q
Record Group numbers: RG-21/30.771 (.772) (.781) (.801) (.811) (.871) (.872) (.881-.884) (.891) (.901) (.902) (.911-.913) (.921) (.922) (.924) (.941) (.951) (.971)
Organization
Group I (Correspondence) contains letters, notes and letter drafts. The arrangement, in keeping with Bowers' filing order, lists a portion of the correspondence chronologically by date and another portion, alphabetically by the correspondent's name. A "Restricted" category contains correspondence whose access is controlled by its donor, Matthew J. Bruccoli.
Group II (Writings), comprising almost 90% of the collection, includes material consisting of copy texts, manuscripts, proofs, background research and related correspondence that Bowers used in the development of his published works. This large volume of material has also been arranged in format and chronology similar to that employed by Bowers in listing his writings. An updated version of that listing with the totality of Bowers' publications, titled, "Fredson Thayer Bowers: A Checklist and Chronology," by Martin C. Battestin may be found in Studies in Bibliography, Vol. 46, (1993) 155- 186.
Group III (Academic and Personal), the remainder of the collection, contains personal memorabilia and material relating to Bowers' academic activities. The arrangement of the Bowers papers mirrors both the breadth of his writing and the incisiveness of his analytical and descriptive methodologies. The material is replete with autograph comments, notations and emendations. Many of the manuscripts and proofs show autograph editing that served as new text for revised publication of the originals. The correspondence with those with whom Bowers worked on his many projects, particularly his former student and later assistant and collaborator, Matthew J. Bruccoli, gives a penetrating insight into the detailed and often laborious task of critical bibliographical editing.
Items of special interest include: A bound typescript of Bowers' 1928 Harvard course-thesis; an autograph manuscript of Walter Wilson Greg's seminal essay, "The Rationale of Copy-Text;" Warren Chappell illustrated letters; John Ciadi and Elder Olson poetry; Shakespeare lecture notes of James Southall Wilson; the manuscript and typescript of Bowers' unpublished lecture, "The Ideal Record Collector" and an unpublished checklist (compiled by John Denniston) that catalogues the almost 1200 classical music reviews that Bowers wrote for the Richmond Times-Dispatch between 1939-67.
Microfilm and video recordings have been transferred to the appropriate custodial sections of the University of Virginia Special Collections Department where they are identified as part of these papers under the following location indicators:
microfilm of Stephen Crane's original manuscripts and story texts and a thesis on his poetry (M-1362-1364); microfilm of the poem, "TheConceited Pedlar," and the play, "The Queene of Corsica," by Thomas Randolph (M-1680); microfilm of articles by Bowers concerning Thomas Dekker's writings, particularly, "Old Fortunatus," and on "Variant readings in some early English plays." (M-1682); microfilm of the dramatized version of Andrea Guarna's "Bellum Grammaticale" (M-1938); videorecordings in the Eminent Scholar/Teachers: Shakespeare Video Series of Bowers' lectures, "Death in Victory: Shakespeare's Tragic Reconciliations" and "Hamlet as Minister and Scourge" (VC-33, 34).
Contents List
- Group I: Correspondence
  - General: (Box 1)
    1950-68
    1970-79
    1980-82
    1983-85
    1986-87
    1988-90, n.d.
  - Named: (Box 2)
    Barrett, Clifton Waller, 1955
    Barrol, J. Leeds, 1971-75
    Blayney, Peter W., 1974
    Boydston, Jo-Ann, 1965-90, n.d. (3 folders)
    Brodsky, Louis D., 1978-89, n.d.
    Bruccoli, Matthew J., 1971-90, n.d.
    Chappell, Warren (with illustrations), 1976-87
  - Ciardi, John (with poetry) 1960 (Box 3)
    Clark, Leonard, 1953
    Cook, Don L. 1979-81, n.d.
    Flannagan, Roy, 1989
    Gainesbarry, J., 1971
    Greetham, David C., 1986-90, n.d.
    Greg, Walter Wilson, 1953
    Grier, Philip M., 1974-77
    Hamblin, Robert W., 1978-80
    Howard-Hill, Trevor H., 1957-89
    King, Robert T., 1971-75
    Kolve, V.A., 1980
    Kvarnes, Robert G., 1977
    Levin, Harry Tuchman, 1982
    Miscellaneous correspondence (other thanbowers), 1967-71
    Reiman, Donald H., 1983-85
    Rosowski, Susan J., 1983-84
    Rowse, A. Leslie, 1973-85
    Shillingsburg, Peter, 1987-88
    Tanselle, G. Thomas, 1976-90, n.d.
    Turner, Robert, 1959-90
    Vander Meulen, David L., 1984-88
    Williams, George W., 1971-89, n.d.
  - [Restricted] General 1961-78 (Box 4)
    [Restricted] Named: Bowers, Nancy Hale (with Bruccoli), 1959-84
    Bruccoli, Matthew J. (with Fredson Thayer Bowers), 1963-87, n.d. (6 folders) (with others), 1967-76
- Group II: Writings
  - Books (Manuscript Material and Proofs)
    - On Editing Shakespeare and the Elizabethan Dramatists 1955 (Box 5)
      - Manuscript material n.d. (Box 5)
    - Textual and Literary Criticism 1959 (Box 5)
      - Manuscript material ca.1957-59 (Box 5)
      - Proofs 1957-59 (Box 5)
    - Hamlet as Minister and Scourge and Other Studies in Shakespeare and Milton 1989 (Box 6)
      - Manuscript material 1980-89, n.d., (4 folders) (Box 6)
      - Proofs (Box 6)
    - The Bibliographical Way 1959 (Box 6)
      - Manuscript material 1958-59 (Box 6)
      - Proofs 1959 (Box 6)
  - Editions (Copy Texts, Manuscript Material, Proofs,Background) (Box 7)
    - The Dramatic Works of Thomas Dekker 1953-1961 (Box 7)
      - Copy texts: Vol. II 1604-08, n.d. (Box 7)
      - Manuscript material: Vol. III 1954, (4 folders) (Box 7)
      - Vol. IV 1951-59, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 8)
      - Proofs: Vol. III, 1954, (2 folders) (Box 8)
      - Vol. IV 1960 (Box 8)
      - Background: Related correspondence 1955-59, n.d. (Box 8)
    - The Centenary Edition of the Works of Nathaniel Hawthorne 1962-1988 (Box 9)
      - Copy texts: Vol. IV ca. 1860, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 9)
      - Vol. V, 1857-63 1965-67, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 9)
      - Vol. VI 1842-51, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 10)
      - Vol. VII 1853 (Box 10)
      - Vol. IX 1838 (Box 10)
      - Vol. XVIII 1850-63 (Box 10)
      - Manuscript material: Vol. I 1962, n.d. (Box 10)
      - Vol. II 1962-64, n.d. (Box 10)
      - Vol. III 1962-63, n.d. (Box 10)
      - Vol. IV 1962-65, n.d. (Box 10)
      - Vol. V 1968, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Vol. VI n.d. (Box 11)
      - Vol. VII n.d. (Box 11)
      - Vol. IX n.d. (Box 11)
      - Vol. X n.d. (Box 11)
      - Vol. XI n.d. (Box 11)
      - Background: Related correspondence 1962-70, n.d. (Box 11)
    - The Dramatic Works in the Beaumont and Fletcher Canon 1966-[]. (Box 12)
      - Copy texts: Vol. II 1615, 1972 (Box 12)
      - Vol. III n.d. (Box 12)
      - Vol. VII 1634, n.d. (Box 12)
      - Vol. VIII 1922 (Box 12)
      - Vol. IX 1637-1845, n.d., (1-5 of 9 folders) (Box 12)
      - Vol. X 1711, 1966, n.d., (6-9 of 9 folders)(2 folders) (Box 13)
      - Manuscript material: Vol. III n.d. (Box 14)
      - Vol. VIII n.d. (Box 14)
      - Vol. IX n.d., (2 folders) (Box 14)
      - Vol. X n.d. (Box 14)
      - Background: Related correspondence and research 1938-90, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 14)
    - The University of Virginia Edition of the Works of Stephen Crane 1969-1976 (Box 15)
      - Copy texts: Vol. II 1894-98, n.d., (1-6 of 10 folders) (Box 15)
      - Box 16, (7-10 of 10 folders)
      - Vol. III 1896-99, 1974-75, n.d., (3 folders) see also oversize (Box 17)
      - Vol. IV n.d., (6 folders) (Box 18)
      - Vol. V 1895-1901, 1969, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 19)
      - Vol. VI 1896-1900, 1968, n.d., (1-7 of 9 folders) (Box 20)
      - Box 21, (8-9 of 9 folders)
      - Vol. VII 1900-02, (2 folders) (Box 21)
      - Vol. VIII 1885-1902, n.d., (1-2 of 31 folders) (Box 21)
      - Box 22, (3-6 of 31 folders)
      - Box 23, (7-11 of 31 folders)
      - Box 24, (12-16 of 31 folders)
      - Box 25, (17-21 of 31 folders)
      - Box 26, (22-26 of 31 folders)
      - Box 27, (27-31 of 31 folders)
      - Vol. IX 1897-98, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 28)
      - Vol. X 1891-99, ca.1973-74, n.d., (1-4 of 8 folders) (Box 29)
      - Box 30, (5-8 of 8 folders)
      - Manuscript material: Vol. IV 1969-70, n.d. (Box 31)
      - Vol. V 1969, n.d. (Box 31)
      - Vol. VI n.d., (2 folders) (Box 31)
      - Vol. VIII 1973, n.d. (Box 32)
      - Vol. IX n.d., (4 folders) (Box 32)
      - Proofs: Vol. I 1968-69, n.d., (1-4 of 7 folders) (Box 33)
      - Box 34, (5-7 of 7 folders)
      - Vol. II 1973-75, (4 folders) (Box 35)
      - Vol. III 1974-76, n.d., (1-4 of 22 folders) (Box 36)
      - Box 37, (5-9 of 22 folders)
      - Box 38, (10-14 of 22 folders)
      - Box 39, (15-17 of 22 folders)
      - Box 40, (18-22 of 22 folders)
      - Vol. IV 1970-71, n.d., (1-6 of 10 folders) (Box 41)
      - Box 42, (7-10 of 10 folders)
      - Vol. V 1970, n.d., (1-5 of 7 folders) (Box 43)
      - Box 44, (6-7 of 7 folders)
      - Vol. VI 1969-70, n.d., (1-4 of 10 folders) (Box 44)
      - Box 45, (5-10 of 10 folders)
      - Vol. VII 1968, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 46)
      - Vol. VIII 1972-73, n.d., (1-5 of 38 folders) (Box 47)
      - Box 48, (6-9 of 38 folders)
      - Box 49, (10-13 of 38 folders)
      - Box 50, (14-17 of 38 folders)
      - Box 51, (18-22 of 38 folders)
      - Box 52, (23-27 of 38 folders)
      - Box 53, (28-32 of 38 folders)
      - Box 54, (33-38 of 38 folders)
      - Vol. IX 1970-71, n.d., (1-5 of 24 folders) (Box 55)
      - Box 56, (6-9 of 24 folders)
      - Box 57, (10-13 of 24 folders)
      - Box 58, (14-19 of 24 folders)
      - Box 59, (20-24 of 24 folders)
      - Vol. X 1974-75, n.d., (1-5 of 15 folders) (Box 60)
      - Box 61, (6-10 of 15 folders)
      - Box 62, (11-15 of 15 folders)
      - Background: Correspondence related to publications 1962-75, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Financial 1969-75, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Miscellaneous 1912, 1967-69, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Photographs and negatives for print illustrations 1968-74, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 63)
      - Stephen and Cora Crane correspondence (EC's) 1894-1973, (1-2 of 6 folders) (Box 63)
      - Box 64, (3-6 of 6 folders)
      - Textual studies of Stephen Crane by Bowers 1945-72, n.d. (Box 64)
    - Stephen Crane, The Red Badge of Courage: A Facsimile Edition of the Manuscript 1972-1973 (Box 65)
      - Manuscript material: Vol. I n.d., (2 folders) (Box 65)
      - Vol. II, n.d. Background: Related correspondence 1970-73, n.d. (Box 65)
    - The Complete Works of Christopher Marlowe 1973 (Box 66)
      - Copy texts: Vol. I 1818-1820, n.d. (Box 66)
      - Vol. II 1595-1818, n.d., (1-3 of 8 folders) see also oversize (Box 66)
      - Box 67, (4-6 of 8 folders)
      - Box 68, (7-8 of 8 folders)
      - Manuscript material: Vols. I and II n.d. (Box 68)
      - Proofs: Vol. II n.d. (Box 68)
      - Background: Related correspondence and miscellaneous notes 1971-80, n.d. (Box 68)
    - The Wesleyan Edition of the Works of Henry Fielding, 1967-[],The History of Tom Jones a Foundling (Box 69)
      - Copy texts 1749, n.d., (1-6 of 17 folders) (Box 69)
      - Box 70, (7-12 of 17 folders)
      - Box 71, (13-17 of 17 folders)
    - Amelia 1937, 1976-82, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 72)
      Manuscript material
      - Copy texts 1762, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 72)
      - Background: Related correspondence 1963, 1984 (Box 72)
    - The Works of William James 1975-1988. (Box 72)
      - Background: Related correspondence and miscellaneous 1975-87
    - Vladimir Nabokov, Lectures on Literature 1980 (Box 73)
      - Copy texts 1978, n.d., (1-5 of 8 folders) (Box 73)
      - Box 74, (6-8 of 8 folders)
      - Proofs 1980 (Box 74)
      - Lectures on Russian Literature 1981 (Box 74)
      - Copy texts 1941, n.d., (1-2 of 5 folders) (Box 74)
      - Box 75, (3-5 of 5 folders)
      - Manuscript material 1979-81, n.d., (1-3 of 4 folders) (Box 75)
      - Box 76, (4 of 4 folders)
      - Proofs 1981, (2 folders) (Box 76)
      - Lectures on Don Quixote 1983 (Box 76)
      - Copy texts n.d., (3 folders) (Box 76)
      - Manuscript material n.d., (4 folders) (Box 77)
      - Proofs 1982 (Box 77)
      - Background: Related correspondence and miscellaneous 1978-82, n.d. (Box 77)
    - Leon Kroll: A Spoken Memoir, with Nancy Hale 1983 (Box 78)
      - Copy texts, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 78)
      - Background: Related correspondence 1969, 1980 (Box 78)
    - "Jacobean and Caroline Dramatists," Dictionary of Literary Biography, Vol 58 1987 (Box 78)
      - Copy texts: "The Malcontent" 1604 (Box 78)
    - The Cambridge Edition of the Works of F. Scott Fitzgerald 1991-. (Box 79)
      - Text analyses: The Beautiful and the Damned1988-89 (Box 79)
      - The Great Gatsby 1973-89 (Box 79)
      - The Last Tycoon 1976 (Box 79)
      - Tender is the Night 1988-89, (1-2 of 4 folders) (Box 79)
      - Box 80, (3-4 of 4 folders)
      - This Side of Paradise 1988-89 (Box 80)
      - Background: Related correspondence and notes 1988-90, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 80)
    - Essays (Manuscript Material and Related Correspondence) (Box 81)
      - Contributions to Serials and Books 1939 (Box 81)
      - "Marriot's Two Editions of Randolph's Aristippus," 1630-51, 1937-38 1954, (2 folders) (Box 81)
      - "Scholarship, Research, and the Undergraduate Teacher," n.d. 1957 (Box 81)
      - "The Earliest Manuscript of Whitman's 'Passage to India' and Its Notebook," n.d. 1958 (Box 81)
      - "Old Spelling Editions of Dramatic Texts," 1957-58 1959 (Box 81)
      - "The Death of Hamlet" n.d. (Box 81)
      - "The Function of Bibliography" 1956-58 (Box 81)
      - "Textual Criticism" n.d. (Box 81)
      - Box 82 1961
      - "The Business of Teaching" 1960 (Box 82)
      - "Sir Walter Wilson Greg" 1960 (Box 82)
      - 1962 (Box 82)
      - "Established Texts and Definitive Editions" 1961 (Box 82)
      - "Henry Vaughan's Multiple Time Scheme" 1960 (Box 82)
      - "Herbert's Sequential Imagery: 'The Temper'" n.d. (Box 82)
      - "What Shakespeare Wrote" n.d. (Box 82)
      - 1966 (Box 82)
      - "Hal and Francis in King Henry IV, Part I" n.d. (Box 82)
      - "Textual Criticism of Shakespeare" 1964 (Box 82)
      - 1967 (Box 82)
      - "Death in Victory: Shakespeare's Tragic Reconciliations" n.d. (Box 82)
      - "Old Wine in New Bottles: Problems of Machine Printing" n.d. (Box 82)
      - 1968 (Box 82)
      - "Practical Texts and Definitive Editions" 1965-68, n.d. (Box 82)
        see also oversize [Review of Charles Dickens, Oliver Twist, ed. K. Tillotson], 1968
      - 1969 (Box 82)
      - "Adam, Eve and the Fall in Paradise Lost" n.d. (Box 82)
      - "Bibliography Revisited" 1967-69 (Box 82)
      - [Review of Walt Whitman's Blue Book, ed. A. Golden] 1968 (Box 82)
      - "Textual Principles and Procedures" 1969 (Box 82)
        see also Box 83
      - 1970 (Box 82)
      - "The New Look in Editing" 1969-70 (Box 82)
      - "On a Future for Graduate Studies" 1970 (Box 82)
      - "Textual Criticism" ca. 1971, n.d. (Box 82)
      - "Theme and Structure in King Henry IV, Part I" 1968-70, n.d. (Box 82)
      - 1971 (Box 82)
      - "Remarks Honoring Clifton Waller Barrett" 1971 (Box 82)
      - Box 83 1972
      - "The Early Editions of Marlowe's Ovid's Elegies" 1971 (Box 83)
      - "Multiple Authority: New Problems and Concepts of Copy-Text" 1971-72, (2 folders) (Box 83)
      - "Seven or More Years" 1971 (Box 83)
      - "Was There a Lost 1593 Edition of Marlowe's Edward II?" 1971 (Box 83)
      - 1973 (Box 83)
      - "McKerrow Revisited" 1972-73 (Box 83)
      - "The Ecology of American Literary Texts" 1973 (Box 83)
      - 1976 (Box 83)
      - "Scholarship and Editing" n.d. (Box 83)
      - 1980 (Box 83)
      - "The Structure of King Lear" 1980 (Box 83)
      - 1982 (Box 83)
      - "Textual Principles and Procedures" 1982 (Box 83)
        see also Box 82
      - 1983 (Box 83)
      - "The Concept of Single or Dual Protagonists in Shakespeare's Tragedies" 1981-82, n.d. (Box 83)
      - [Review of Hamlet (New Arden Edition), ed. H. Jenkins] 1982 (Box 83)
      - 1986 (Box 83)
      - "Authority, Copy, and Transmission in Shakespeare's Texts" n.d. (Box 83)
      - "A Search for Authority: The Investigation of Shakespeare's Texts" 1982, n.d. (Box 83)
      - Box 84 1987
      - "Mixed Texts and Multiple Authority" n.d. (Box 84)
      - "Readability and Regularization in Old-Spelling Texts of Shakespeare" n.d. (Box 84)
      - 1988 (Box 84)
      - "Unfinished Business" 1985, n.d. (Box 84)
      - 1989 (Box 84)
      - "Regularization and Normalization in Modern Critical Texts" 1987, n.d. (Box 84)
      - 1990 (Box 84)
      - "Death in Victory: Shakespeare's Tragic Reconciliations" 1987-90, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 84)
      - "Hamlet as Minister and Scourge" 1990 (Box 84)
      - "The Problem of Semi-Substantive Variants: An Example from the Shakespeare-Fletcher Henry VIII" 1988-90 (Box 84)
      - 1991 (Box 84)
      - "Authorial Intention and Editorial Problems" 1988-89 (Box 84)
      - 1992 (Box 84)
      - "Why Apparatus?" 1990 (Box 84)
    - Essay Drafts (Publication Undetermined) (Box 85)